Contact

0613513831 (Mobile) mtetwabongumusa@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/bongumusamtetwa-248365210 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Git

Unit Testing

Java Tools

Certifications

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

Introduction to Java and Object-Oriented Programming

Bongumusa Mtetwa

Software developer

City of Johannesburg, Gauteng, South Africa

Summary

Experienced software developer who is reliable, self-motivated, dedicated and a proficient team player with an incredible work ethic. Currently working towards establishing a strong reputation as a developer and leader within the software development community.

Skilled in Java, JavaScript, JSON, Agile & Waterfall Methodologies, Critical Thinking, Troubleshooting, and Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) at ELO Digital Office and have been enjoying it. I am currently exploring cloud development and ensuring that I get exposure to deploying solutions and applications on the cloud. I am comfortable with working with Java, JavaScript, JSON, and C# to name a few. I would like to get more exposure to more frontend frameworks to expand my knowledge and merge into full-stack JavaScript development in the near future. I am highly adaptive to new concepts with excellent listening and analytical skills.

I am highly adaptive to change and still regard myself as an exeprienced novice in the world of software development world. However, learning each day by enabling technology and innovation to solve complex problems.

"If, at first, you do not succeed, call it version 1.0. – Khayri R.R. Woulfe"

Experience

ELO Digital Office Africa (Pty) Ltd. Software Developer January 2021 - Present (2 years 9 months) South Africa

For the past 2 years I've been part of a hard-working, passionate, and openminded team at ELO Digital Office. I have worked in numerous projects including:

Records Management Systems: These were multiple implementations assisting ministries and companies in managing their records and be able to retrive them with ease whilst adhering to legislatives standards. My role was to develop this solutions in our platform and ensuring that these systems are useable.

Contract Management Solutions: In the past years we have developed solution that assist various sectors in managing their contracts. These projects allowed customers to manage the complete contract lifecycle, allowing them to monitor contracts with ease while saving costs and increasing on revenue.

Human Resources Solutions: These solutions range from Candidate management, Personnel management, and placement. We implemented diverse solutions to various sectors and sizes, allowing myself to get more exposure in this aspect and acquire experience in Human Resources applications.

Khanya Africa Networks Network Technician June 2019 - December 2019 (7 months) Durban, KwaZulu-Natal, South Africa

In this work experience at Khanya Africa Networks, it was an internships which gave me experience in the infrastructure domain of IT and offered great exposure to the working world.

Education

Berea College of Technology

Diploma in Information Technology, Information Technology · (January 2017 - December 2019)